and today we're going to learn how to
use the newly announced chat GPT API and
we are also going to see what kind of
products we can build with it I'm sure
that by now you know about cha GB3 and
how mind-blowing it is but what you may
not know is that you can actually build
products on top of chatgpt or integrate
charge GPT in your already existing
websites and apps by using the chat GPT
API you can not only call chargeivity
from within your code but you can also
customize and fine-tune chat GPT
according to what your business needs
are this means that you can have a
chatbot with the power of chat GPT that
also knows how to reply to your users or
customers about specific questions about
your business to get inspiration on what
we can build with this API we can look
at instacart a grocery delivery app they
are using charge gbt and their own
product data to build a better search
experience where the users can ask for
ideas about what to cook or what is a
healthy meal and receive an answer by
charge GPT with ideas that use products
they can shop for Shopify is also using
charge gbt on their own app shop as a
shopping assistant the extended charge
GPT and added the products on their
database which makes it possible for
chatgpt to search the store database and
recommend products that the user is
looking for and is able to buy I hope
this gives you an idea of the kind of
things you can build with this API so
let's talk about it and see how we can
use it open AI the company behind
chargeupt has had an API for a while but
what they announced some days ago is the
release of the model GPT 3.5 turbo which
is the same model used on the chat GPT
product that we have all seen before the
reason why this model is making news is
because of how cheap it is to use it
according to open AI thanks to some
optimizations that they made the new
model is 10 times cheaper than the
previous one bringing the price to
0.002 dollars per 1000 tokens when you
send a question to chat GPT that
question is chopped into pieces called
tokens sometimes a word is a token and
sometimes a long word will be split on
multiple tokens a token is just a
sequence of characters and chat Deputy
is very good at predicting what the next
token on a sequence of tokens will be
here you can see how the question what
is the distance between the Moon and the
Sun plus the answer that we receive
gives us a total of 54 tokens with those
numbers we can ask questions like that
thousands of times before we pay the
first two dollars that is super cheap to
get started with the API jump on
platform.openai.com and either log in or
create an account and then go to the API
Keys page and generate your API key they
will only show you the API key once so
make sure to copy paste it somewhere
safe after that on a computer that has
python installed open your console and
run pip install open AI all these left
is to start talking to chargeipity using
our code on a new python file we will
will import openai we will set our API
key which by the way is secret so make
sure to protect it and after we will
create a new chat completion we will
choose the latest GPT 3.5 durable model
and then we will write down a message as
you can see the message has a role which
we will talk about later and a Content
which is where we will put our question
finally we will print the completion to
the console to get an output like this
as you can see we receive a choice
inside of a list of choices with the
response from chat GPT we can also see
on the usage key the amount of tokens
our question took the amount the
response took and the total tokens that
we spend as you saw before when we are
sending a message to chat GPT we are
specifying a role for each message there
are three kinds of roles that we can use
system user and assistant we use the
user role when we want to ask something
directly to chat GPT as if you were a
user chatting with we use the system
role when we want to initialize or
configure the model before it receives a
message from the user for example in
this code you can see how we are sending
two messages one with system role and
one with user role we use the system
role to initialize the assistant telling
it that it is a helpful kindergarten
teacher talking to children so when we
ask it to explain what AI is we get a
response like this one that starts by
saying hello kids today we're going to
learn blah blah blah uses easy language
and examples tailored for kids and
finishes with isn't that amazing if we
instead change the code to look like
this and we set up our model as if it
was a PhD teacher talking to students
the response will be more complex using
more complex words and telling us that
PhD students should have a basic
understanding of AI the other role we
can use is the assistant role that one
we can use to indicate that the message
it was a message previously sent by chat
GPT it is useful for when we are saving
the conversation between the user and
the assistant and we want to provide the
previous messages to the assistant which
might influence their response so with
this code we are telling chargeivity
that the user previously asked who owns
Tesla and that charge GPT previously
answered that Elon Musk owns it and then
we ask how much did he pay for it if we
only asked how much did he pay for it
the AI won't know what we are talking
about but using the assistant role we
can provide messages of a previous
conversation getting an answer that
talks about Elon and Tesla roles are
pretty cool and all but the thing that I
like the most and what I think many
businesses are going to be using is the
fine tuning API which as of today is not
supported on the new GPT 3.5 models but
it is supported with the other gpd3
models like Da Vinci Curry and babach
using fine tuning you can sort of train
the model with your own custom data so
for example if you wanted to train a
model to detect if a customer is happy
or not you will first get the data from
your database and write down what the
ideal completion will be like here for
example we are explicitly telling the
model what a positive and negative
review is when the motor sees a similar
review it can detect if it's positive or
negative of course we need hundreds of
examples to achieve a better quality but
being able to fine-tune the model is
great you don't have to build a language
model yourself you can inherit all the
power of the gpt3 and add the extra
things that are specific to your company
or business needs fine tuning a model is
a little bit more complex and takes more
steps so let me know in the comments if
you would like me to make a full
tutorial on how to use the open AI API
and other models as wet as you can see
it is pretty easy to talk to chat GPT
from your code and the things you can
build with it are super cool all you
have to know is know a little bit of
Python and you are good to go if you
want to Learn Python for absolutely free
with me then click the link below there
you will find a free six hour course
where you will learn python from xero
the course is for absolute beginners and
you can join right now for free by
clicking the link below join now for
free and I will see you there
mobile see you on the next one bye
thank you